[{"question":"<p><strong>A man and wife went to buy an article costing N400. The woman had 10% of the cost and the man 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N216","N200","N184","N144"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Add the same number to the numerator and denominator of <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>18<\/sub>&nbsp;If the resulting fraction is <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;then the number added is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["13","14","15","12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>After getting a rise of 15%, a man\u2019s new monthly salary is N345 How much per month did he earn before the increase?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N330","N96.75","N300","N293.25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Assuming <em>log<\/em><sub>e<\/sub> 4.4 = 1.4816&nbsp; and&nbsp; <em>log<\/em><em><sub>e<\/sub><\/em> 7.7 = 2.0142, then the value of <em>log<\/em><sub>e<\/sub>&nbsp; (<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.5326","3.4958","0.4816","0.0142"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate correct to 4 decimal places 827.51 x 0.015.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8.8415","12.4127","124.1265","12.4120"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express 130 kilometres per second in metres per hour<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7.8 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>","468 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>","7,800,000","4.68 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a circular paper disc is trimmed in such a way that its circumference is reduced in the ratio 2:5, in what ratio is the area reduced?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8:125","2:5","8:25","4:25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In base ten, the number 101101 (base 2) equals<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","4","45","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The annual profits of a transport business were divided between the two partners A and B&nbsp;in the ratio 3:5.&nbsp; If B receives N3,000 more than A, the total profit was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N5,000","N1,800","N12,000","N24,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The diameter of a metal rod is measured as 23.40cm to four significant figures. What is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>the maximum error in the measurement?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.05cm","0.5cm","0.045cm","0.005cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ratio of the price of a loaf of bread to the price of a packet of sugar in 1975 was <em>r<\/em> :<em>t<\/em>&nbsp;in 1980 the price of a loaf went up by 25% and that of a packet of sugar by 10%. Their new ratio is now<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40r:50t","44r:50t","50r:44t","55r:44t"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two distinct sectors in the same circle subtend 100\u00b0 and 30\u00b0 respectively at the centre of the circle. Their corresponding arcs are in the ratio<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1:100","3:1","5:2","10:3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the number whose logarithm to base 10 is 2.3482?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["223.6","0.2228","2.235","222.9"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a dealer sells a bicycle for N81 he makes a profit of 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N73","N74.52","N75","N75.52"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A father is now three times as old as his son. Twelve years ago, he was six times as old as&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>his son. How old are the son and the father?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20 and 45","100 and 150","45 and 65","20 and 60"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three consecutive positive integers a, b and c are such that b<sup>2<\/sup> = 4(a + c). Find the value of c<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","3","9","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the principal which amount to N4,400 at simple interest in 5years at 2% per annum<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N3,800","N5.200","N5,000","N4,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Robson bought bags of orange for N2,500 each. He sold them for N90,000 at a loss of 20%. How many bags of orange did he buy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","80","50","45"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The second and fifth terms of a geometric progression are 21 and 567 respectively, find the first term and the common ratio of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3, 7","7, 3","-7, 3","-3, 7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Tunse bought a house for N1,250,000 and spent N350,000.00 to renovate it. He then sold the house for N2,000,000.00. What is the percentage gain?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40%","65%","35%","25%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>List the integral values of which satisfy the inequality -2 &lt; 7 &ndash; 3x = 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-1, 0, 1, 2","-2, 0, 1","1, 2, 3","0, 1,2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The lengths of the sides of a right angled triangle are ym, (3y \u2013 1)m and (3y + 1)m, find y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","9","8","4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Uche, Adamu and Ope share profit on a business deal. Uche received <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> of the profit and Adamu received <sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> of the remainder. If Ope received the remaining N12,000, how much profit did they share?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N54,000","N58,000","N48,000","N42,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A ladder resting on a vertical wall makes an angle whose tangent is 2.5 with the ground. If the distance between the foot of the ladder and the wall is 60cm, what is the length of the ladder?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2m","1.6m","0.8m","3m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three students share a bag of garri in such a way that the first student took <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> of the garri and the second,&nbsp;<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> of the remainder What fraction of the bag of garri did the third student take?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>16<\/sub>","<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>16<\/sub>","<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>15<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x + 1 is a factor of x<sup>3<\/sup> + 3x<sup>2<\/sup> + Kx + 4, find the value of K<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","4","-4","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Paul and his friend, Peter went to buy an article costing N600. Peter had 10% of the cost and Paul 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N320","N440","N276","N196"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find all values of x satisfying the inequality -14 &le; 4 &ndash; 3x &le; 31<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-6 \u2264 x \u2264 9","-9 \u2264 x \u2264 6","5 \u2264 x \u2264 8","6 \u2264 x \u2264 12"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What factor is common to all the expressions x<sup>2<\/sup> - x, 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - x - 1 and x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2x -1)","(x +1)","(x -1)","(2x +3)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the number of sides of a regular polygon whose interior angle is twice the exterior angle<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","6","8","9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of p, if the line which passes through (-1, -p) and (-2p, 2) is parallel to the line 2y + 8x&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>&ndash; 17 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>6<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>","<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>","<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>","-<sup>6<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Obtain a maximum value of the function f(x) = x<sup>3<\/sup> - 12x + 11<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-15","27","15","20"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y = 5cos (-6x), <sup>dy<\/sup>\/<sub>dx<\/sub> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30sin (-6x)","5sin (-6x)","-30sin (-6x)","-30cos (-6x)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the variance of the numbers k, k + 1, k + 2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/3","3","2\/3","1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what value of x is the function y = x<sup>2<\/sup> - 6x - 7 minimum<br><\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","5","6","2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x and y represent the mean and the median respectively of the following marks of students in a Mathematics test 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 21. Find&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>\/<sub>y<\/sub>&nbsp;correct to 1 decimal places.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.0","3.0","5.0","2.0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the point on the Euclidean plane where the curve y = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x + 9 has 2 as gradient<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2, 4)","(3, 5)","(1, 9)","(1, 4)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line through (5, 7) parallel to the line 7x + 5y &ndash; 5 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5y + 7x = 70","7x + 5y = 7","5x + 7y = 110","y + 5x = 70"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the distance between points A(-4, 5) and B(-3, 2)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","2\u221a5","3","\u221a10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<table class=\"table table-bordered\"><tbody><tr><td><b>No of children<br><\/b><\/td><td><b>0<\/b><\/td><td><b>1<\/b><\/td><td><b>2<\/b><\/td><td><b>3<\/b><\/td><td><b>4<\/b><\/td><td><b>5<\/b><\/td><\/tr><tr><td><b>No of families<br><\/b><\/td><td><b>7<\/b><\/td><td><b>11<\/b><\/td><td><b>6<\/b><\/td><td><b>7<\/b><\/td><td><b>7<\/b><\/td><td><b>5<\/b><\/td><\/tr><\/tbody><\/table><p><b>&nbsp;Find the mode and median respectively of the distribution above<\/b><\/p>","options":["3, 1","1, 2","1, 6","1, 1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Rationalize <sup>(4\u221a7 + \u221a2)<\/sup>\/<sub>(\u221a2 - \u221a7)<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>","options":["-\u221a14 - 6","2\u221a14 - 6","-3\u221a14 - 28","\u221a14 - 8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A housewife bought five yams at Y34 per yam and three oranges at Y5 each where Y is the currency reckoned in base six. The total amount spent by the housewife is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Y225<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y252<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y315<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y352<sub> 6<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Divide the L.C.M. of 36, 54 and 90 by their HCF<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","20","18","45"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 125<sub>x<\/sub> = 20<sub>10<\/sub> find x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","5","3","2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The number 327,036 was corrected to 327,000. Which of the following can exactly describe the degree of approximation used?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>I. to 3 significant figures <\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>II. to&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><strong><em>4 significant figures<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>III. to the nearest hundred&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>IV.&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><strong><em>to the nearest thousand<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["I and III only","I and IV only","I, II and III only","I, II, III and IV"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 101010<sub>2<\/sub> = x<sub>10<\/sub> + 1111<sub>2<\/sub> the value of x is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["32","27","19","13"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The population of a school is 1,376. Express this to three significant figures<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1,370","1,376","1,380","138"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of x if 4logx + 5logx &ndash; 7logx = log16<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","8","16"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A motorist drives from P to Q at an average speed of 80km\/hr and immediately returns from Q to P through the same route at an average speed of 50km\/hr. The average speed for the round-trip journey is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["53.3km\/hr","60.0km\/hr","61.5km\/hr","65.0km\/hr"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If X = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}, Y = {2, 4, 5, 7} and Z = {1, 4, 5} which of the following is (are) correct?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I. n(X U Y U Z) = 13<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>II. (X &cap; Y) U Z = X &cap; (Y U Z)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>III. n(X &cap; Y &cap; Z) = 2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I only","II only","I and III only","II and III only"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>X sold a radio set to Y at profit of 10% and Y sold it for N2,612.50 at a loss of 5%. The&nbsp;cost of the radio to X was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N2,500","N2,488","N2,375","N2,272"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum point on the curve y = x<sup>2<\/sup> &ndash; 4x + 3 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2, -1)","(0, 3)","(1, 0)","(2, -4)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"}]